CALVIN NJUGUNA NGUGI

Tel: 0701141934 | Email: ncalvin67@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/Calvin-Ngugi/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/calvin-ngugi/
Portfolio: https://my-portfolio-calvin-ngugi.vercel.app/

PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm a Professional Full Stack Software Engineer with experience building out both consumer and start-up applications, including web applications and with various technologies. I like to communicate my thoughts and ideas, while also learning better ways to solve problems

SKILLS

- o Proficient in working with java maven and vertx to build backend projects.
- Worked with advance web development technologies like React, NextJs, Laravel, Express, Node, JavaScript, Bootstrap and tailwind
- o Proficient in working with database technologies such as Microsoft SQL Server for relational databases, Firebase and MongoDB for non-relational databases
- o Experience using version control systems such as Git.
- o Operating system and applications installation and management
- o Good analytical, Interpersonal & Organizational Skills
- o Critical thinking

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

06/2022 – 01/2023: **Software Engineering - Moringa School**

2017 – 2021: **Bachelor of Science: Information Technology -** Kabarak University

08/2020 – 11/2020: Google IT support and Networking

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Oct 2023 to Present

AO Technology Group Ltd

- Led the backend development for a comprehensive hotel management system, including POS, reservation, stock management, and report generation.
- Team development of systems using Laravel and SQL server database.
- Innovatively introduced React to maintain state in our applications, enhancing their efficiency and responsiveness.
- Developed robust backend systems for T24 using Maven and Java, improving system performance and reliability.

Intern – Open Source Developer

Feb 2023 to August 2023

iTalanta from Elewa Company

- Contributed significantly to open-source projects for the Elewa group, demonstrating strong collaborative and technical skills.
- Working in a team to properly complete tasks assigned
- Effectively utilized Firebase and Firestore for database management and Angular for frontend development, ensuring project completion and functionality.

Techware Enterprises Limited

Technician – Corporate Client Support Junior Technician – Corporate Client Support

Jan 2022 to Jul 2022 May 2021 to Sep 2021

- Successfully created and launched the company website (https://techware.co.ke/), enhancing the company's online presence.
- Expertly troubleshot and resolved system failures and bugs, restoring optimal functionality for clients' machines.
- Installed and configured software and hardware to meet client specifications, ensuring seamless operation.
- Provide orientation and guidance to users on how to operate new software and computer equipment

Community work – Junior Communications Officer Africa Youth Trust

Sep 2021 to Oct 2021

- Monitored and reported web, email, and social media analytics to management, providing actionable insights.
- Updated the organization's website using WordPress, ensuring current project information was readily accessible.
- Enhanced the company's social media presence by consistently updating platforms with relevant content.

PROJECTS

E-waiter App - https://e-waiter.vercel.app/

This is a restaurant app, built with react and firebase, that helps the restaurant by letting the customer choose a dish and order. Human waiters will only be delivering the dishes to the tables that have ordered.

Lunar Beauty Parlour Website- https://beauty-parlor.vercel.app/

This a marketing website I made for a beauty shop called Lunar Beauty Parlour and spa. It was created using react and the animation done using framer motion.

Connectify - https://connectify-lime.vercel.app/

Connectify is a social platform that allows users to read posts and follow users. To access all features, one needs to be a premium membership. Login details are the username and zipcode for <u>users table</u>

REFEREES

- Vincent Buseretse
 Senior Credit Analyst
 NCBA Bank
- Hesbone Ndungu
 Executive Director
 Africa Youth Trust

3. Charles NgugiManaging DirectorTechware Enterprises Limited